[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Next, we're going to take a few minutes to talk about the famous AdaBoost theorem and
فيما يلي سنستغرق بضع دقائق، للتحدث بشأن نظرية AdaBoost الشهيرة
what it's practical implications are, which are extremely interesting.
وماهي آثارها العملية، التي تكون مثيرة للاهتمام جدًا.
So, if you remember, the way that boosting came about is that Kearns and Valiant
لذلك، إذا كنت تتذكر، الطريقة التي ظهر بها التعزيز هي أنه رواد "كيرنز" و"فاليانت"
had this famous question, can you combine weak classifiers to make a stronger one?
هذا السؤال الشهير، هل يمكنك دمج مصنفات ضعيفة لإنشاء آخر قوي؟
Actually, Valiant is a touring award winner, so
في الواقع، فاليانت هو فائز بجائرة توزنغ، لذلك
really famous professor from Harvard.
هو أستاذ شهير للغاية بجامعة هارفارد.
And Schapire, a couple of years later,
وبعد عامين توصل شابيري
came up with the idea of boosting, which really changed the machine learning field.
لفكرة التعزيز، مما غير مجال التعلم الآلي حقًا.
And so if you look at the iterations of
وهكذا، إذا نظرت إلى تكرار
boosting in the x axis here, in the training error for our dataset,
التعزيز في المحور x هنا، في خطأ التدريب لمجموعة البيانات الخاصة بنا.
we observe a very practical effect that we see in a lot of boosting data.
نلاحظ تأثير عملي للغاية نراه في كثير من بيانات التعزيز.
We're going to start with a really bad training error.
سنبدأ بخطأ تدريب سيئ حقًا.
So first decision stump has training error of 22.5%.
لذا فإن أول جذع قرار له خطأ تدريب يبلغ 22.5%.
So, not good at all.
لذا، ليس جيدًا على الإطلاق.
After thirty iterations, as we saw a little earlier,
وبعد ثلاثين مرة من التكرار، كما شاهدنا منذ قليل،
we're going to get all the data points right in our training data and
وسنقوم بالحصول على كافة نقاط البيانات بشكل صحيح في بياناتنا التدريب
I showed you kind of that crazy decision boundary for this.
وقد أظهرت لك نوعًا من حد القرار المجنون لهذا.
So we see a smooth transition where the classification error tends to go down.
لذلك نرى انتقالًا سلسًا حيث يميل خطأ التصنيف للانخفاض إلى أسفل.
Tends to go down and the value goes to zero and actually stays at zero.
ويميل إلى الانخفاض وتذهب القيمة إلى الصفر، ويبقى في الواقع عند مستوى الصفر.
And that's a key insight of the boosting theorem.
وهذه فكرة رئيسية لنظرية التعزيز.
So here is the famous AdaBoost Theorem which underlines all the choices
لذا نرى هنا نظرية AdaBoost الشهيرة الذي يحدد جميع الخيارات
we made in the algorithm and really has had a lot of impact on machine learning.
التي قمنا بها في الخوارزمية وكان لديها الكثير من الأثر حقًا على التعلم الآلي.
Basically the theorem says under some technical conditions and
وتقول النظرية بشكل أساسي إنه تحت بعض الظروف التقنية
all theorems are like this.
تكون جميع النظريات مثل هذا.
Now if you were to be able to say some restrictions apply, see store for details.
الآن إذا كنت لتكون قادرًا على القول بأن بعض القيود تنطبق، راجع المتجر للحصول على التفاصيل.
And so you say under some technical conditions,
ولذا نقول تحت بعض الشروط الفنية،
the training error of the classifier goes to zero, ss the number of
خطأ التدريب للتصنيف يذهب إلى الصفر، وكذلك عدد
iterations of the number and some models considered capital T goes to infinity.
تكرارات العدد وبعض النماذج التي تعتبر أن T تذهب إلى اللانهاية.
So in other words pictorially we'll see that we expect the training error,
لذلك وبعبارة أخرى وبشكل تصويري سنرى أن نتوقع خطأ التدريب،
which is this thing here on the y axis, to go eventually to zero.
وهو هذا الشيء هنا على المحور y، للانتقال في نهاية المطاف إلى الصفر.
Now that's eventually.
والآن في نهاية المطاف.
It might oscillate a little bit in the middle, however,
قد تتذبذب قليلًا في الوسط، ومع ذلك،
what the theorem says is that it tends to generally decrease,
ما تقوله النظرية هو إنه يميل إلى الانخفاض عمومًا،
eventually become zero, usually, and then stick at zero.
ويصبح في نهاية المطاف صفر، ثم يستقر عند مستوى الصفر.
So we're going to see this high in the beginning, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, but
ولذلك سنرى هذا الارتفاع في البداية، ثم تذبذب، تذبذب، ولكن
tends to go down, and then hit a certain value, usually zero, and sticks at zero.
يميل إلى الذهاب إلى أسفل، ومن ثم يصل إلى قيمة معينة، وعادةً ما تكون صفرًا، وتستمر عند الصفر.
Now, let me just take a minute to talk about those
الآن، اسمحوا لي بأن أقوم بأخذ دقيقة للحديث عن
technical distances starts with details.
بدايات المسافات التقنية تلك بالتفاصيل.
It turns out the technical condition is something quite important.
وقد تبين أن الشرط التقني هو شيء مهم جدًا.
It says that at every iteration T, we can find a weak learner.
وهو يقول إنه في كل تكرار T، يمكننا أن نجد متعلمًا ضعيفًا.
So a decision stump that has weighted error at least
لذا فإن جذع القرار له خطأ مرجح يبلغ على الأقل
a little bit lower than 0.5.
أقل قليلًا من 0.5.
So it is at least better than random.
لذا فهي على الأقل أفضل من العشوائية.
That's what the theorem says.
وهذا ما تقوله النظرية.
It seems like intuitively, it would show us by the classifier
ويبدو أن من البديهي، أنه سيظهر لنا بواسطة التصنيف
that it's better than random, even with the data.
أن هذا أفضل من العشوائية، حتى مع البيانات.
But, it turns out that this is not always possible.
ولكن اتضح بأن هذا ليس ممكنًا دائمًا.
So, here is a counter example, which is a really extreme counter example,
لذا، ها هو مثال متناقض، وهو حقًا مثال متناقض متطرف،
but there's other examples where it's not possible.
ولكن هناك أمثلة أخرى حيث من غير الممكن.
So for example, if you have a negative point here,
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا كانت لديك نقطة سلبية هنا،
and you have a positive point on top of it, there's never going to be a decision
ولديك نقطة إيجابية فوقها، فلن يكون هناك فرع قرار
stump that can separate the positive point on top of the negative point.
يمكنه أن يفصل هذه النقطة الإيجابية على رأس هذه النقطة السلبية.
So the conditions of boosting algorithm might not be satisfied,
لذا قد لا تتم تلبية شروط خوارزمية التعزيز،
of the boosting AdaBoost theorem.
من نظرية AdaBoost للتعزيز.
However, nevertheless, boosting usually takes your training error to zero or
ومع ذلك، على الرغم من ذلك، عادة ما يأخذ التعزيز خطأ التدريب الخاص بك إلى الصفر أو
somewhere quite low if the number of iterations go to infinity.
في مكان منخفض جدًا إذا كان عدد مرات التكرار سيذهب إلى اللانهاية.
So, we do observe that decreasing practice although they're are some technical
لذا، نلاحظ ممارسة التناقص على الرغم من أن هناك بعض
conditions in theorems, so it might not go exactly to zero, but it can get really,
الشروط التقنية في النظريات، حيث إنها قد لا تذهب بالضبط إلى الصفر، ولكن قد تصبح حقًا،
really low.
منخفضة للغاية.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]